不敢相信 都过了半小时了
This is unbelievable. It's been half an hour.
要是这是卡通 你到时都变成火腿了
If this was a cartoon, you'd be looking like a ham right about now.
服务生来了 抱歉喔
There's the waitress. Excuse me, miss.
- 小姐？ - 是菲比
- Hello, miss?     - It's Phoebe.
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.     - Hi.
就点这些吗？
Okay, will that be all?
等等 你这是干嘛？
Wait, wait. What are you doing here?
我刚在那边
Yeah, um, I was over there...
然后你们说"抱歉小姐" 所以我就过来啦
...then you said, "Excuse me, miss." So now I'm here.
不是啦 你怎么会在这上班？
No, no. How come you're working here?
对 因为离我住处近 而且围裙很可爱
Right. Because it's close to where I live, and the aprons are really cute.
从头来一遍好吗？
Can we start over?
- 好 很好 我回那边去   - 不 不…
- Yeah. Okay, great. I'll be over here.     - No, no, no, no.
不知是不是在考验我 还是作作样子
I don't know whether he's testing me or just acting out...
但我的猴子真的失控了
...but my monkey is out of control.
可是他一直把答录机上的留言删除
He keeps erasing the messages on my machine.
应该不是故意的
Supposedly by accident.
这事我干过
Oh, yeah, I've done that.
连续三天他抢在我前面拿走报纸
And three days in a row, he got to the newspaper before I did...
在填字游戏上尿尿
...and peed all over the crossword.
这我可没干过
I've never done that.
你看一眼 跟我说她和她姐姐长得不像
Now tell me she doesn't look exactly like her sister.
我觉得不一样啊
I'm saying I see a difference.
她们可是双胞胎耶
They're twins.
不在乎 菲比是菲比 乌苏拉很辣
I don't care. Phoebe's Phoebe. Ursula's hot.
我们说过的那件事 还记得吗？
You know that thing when we talk about things?
- 不要再做了如何   - 好
- Let's not do that anymore.     - Okay.
嘿 各位
Hey, guys. Hey.
菲比 猜猜今天我们遇到谁了
Hey, Pheebs. Guess who we saw today.
有趣 好
Ooh. Oh, fun. Okay.
- 连姆•尼森   - 不是
- Um, Liam Neeson.     - No.
- 莫利•萨佛   - 不是
- Morley Safer.     - Nope.
- 我的发型师   - 不
- The woman who cuts my hair.     - No.
这样玩下去没完没了
Look, this could be a really long game.
你姐姐乌苏拉
Your sister, Ursula.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
- Oh, really?     - Yeah.
她在那个地方上班
She works at that place, uh...
瑞夫餐馆 我知道
Riff's. Yeah, I know.
你知道？她说你们好几年不讲话了
Oh, you do? She said you guys haven't talked in years.
是啊
Hmm? Yeah.
她胖了吗？
So, um, is she fat?
从我角度来看是没有
Not from where I was standing.
你是什么角度？
Where were you standing?
菲比 你们两个处不来吗？
Uh, Pheebs, so you guys just don't get along?
就一些姐妹间的小事
It's mostly just dumb sister stuff, you know?
大家都说她比较漂亮
Everyone always thought of her as the pretty one.
她也先学会走路
Oh. Oh. She was the first to walk...
虽然我只比她晚几小时
...even though I did it later that same day.
但在我父母眼中就不稀罕了
To my parents, by then it was, "Yeah, what else is new?"
哦
Oh.
菲比 真抱歉 我要走了 我要上无痛分娩课
Pheebs, I'm sorry. I've gotta go. I've got Lamaze class.
我要上地球科学课 不过我们健身房见？
Oh, and I've got earth science, but I'll catch you in gym?
只有你和卡萝会去吗？
So is this just gonna be you and Carol?
没 苏珊也会去
No. Susan will be there too.
老爸 女同志 家长成员都到了
We've got dads. We've got lesbians. The whole parenting team.
这不会尴尬吗？
Well, isn't that gonna be weird?
不会 一开始或许会
No. It might have been at first...
但现在我已经很自在了
...but now I'm comfortable with the situation.
- 罗斯 那是我的外套   - 我知道
- Ross, that's my jacket.     - I know.
我们是罗斯丹家
Hi. We're the Rostens.
我是洁西 他是麦可
I'm J.C. And he's Michael.
我怀的是龙凤胎
And we're having a boy and a girl.
厉害 下一对
Good for you. Alrighty, next?
大家好
Hi. Um, I'm, uh... Ahem.
我是罗斯•盖勒
I'm Ross Geller.
肚子里是我儿子
And, uh, that's my boy in there.
这位是卡萝•威利克 这位是苏珊•邦奇
And, uh, this is Carol Willick, and this is Susan Bunch.
苏珊是卡萝的…
Susan is, um, Carol's...
谁是下一对？
Who's next?
抱歉我没听清楚 苏珊是…
I'm sorry, Susan is?
- 苏珊是卡萝的朋友   - 是终生伴侣
- Susan is Carol's friend.     - Life partner.
就好朋友
Like buddies.
是情人
Like lovers.
女人不都这么亲吗
You know how close women can get.
- 苏珊跟我住一起   - 不过跟她结婚的是我
- Susan and I live together.     - I was married to her.
- 是卡萝 不是我   - 有点复杂
- Carol. Not me.     - It's a little complicated.
- 但我们相安无事   - 没错
- But we're fine.     - Absolutely.
所以双胞胎喔
So, twins. Ha.
像生两胎一样
That's like two births.
喔
Ouch.
你也一样 海伦
To you too, Helen.
妮娜•布克邦德到了
Nina Bookbinder is here to see you.
好 请她进来
Oh. Okay, send her in.
你好
Hi.
- 请进   - 你找我？
- Hi, Nina. Come on in.     - You wanted to see me?
是 刚在看你资料
Uh, yes. Uh, I was just going over your data.
你一直把礼拜五的数字往后延
You've been postdating your Friday numbers.
你觉得这样不好 原因是？
Which is bad, because?
- 这有损我的周网量   - 哈哈
- Well, it throws my WENUS out of whack.     - Ha, ha.
抱歉没听懂
Excuse me?
周网量
WENUS. Ahem.
- 每周预估…   - 网路用量系统
- Weekly Estimated...     - Oh, Net Usage Statistics.
喔 懂了懂了
Right. Gotcha, gotcha.
不会再犯了 我不会让你的...
Won't happen again. I wouldn't want to do anything to hurt your...
周网量受到减损
...WENUS.
她不仅可爱好吗？而且还是…
It's not just that she's cute, okay? It's just that...
非常非常可爱
...she's really, really cute.
没差啦 兔子不吃窝边草
It doesn't matter. You don't dip your pen in the company ink.
罗斯
Ross.
你的小动物又去拿遥控器了
Your little creature's got the remote again.
马塞尔 把遥控器给罗斯
Marcel. Marcel, give Rossy the remote.
马塞尔
Marcel.
马塞尔 立刻把遥控器给罗斯
Marcel, you give Rossy the remote right now.
把遥控器…
You give Rossy the remote...
- 好极了   - 别紧张 我会搞定
- Great.     - Relax. I'll fix it.
好耶 厄寇 西班牙文版也叫厄寇
Oh, cool. Urkel in Spanish is Urkel.
他怎么办到的？
How did he do this?
请问一下喔 圣诞灯一直开着
So tell me, is leaving the Christmas lights up...
是要让大家整年快乐吗？
...part of your plan to keep us merry all year long?
有人答应要在新年拆掉灯的
No, someone was supposed to take them down around New Year's...
但显然忘了
...but obviously someone forgot.
有人该写张纸条
Well, someone was supposed to write:
叫瑞秋去拆灯 再把纸条贴在冰箱上的
"Rach, take down the lights," and put it on the refrigera...
纸条贴多久了？
How long has that been there?
你上哪去了？
Hey, where you been?
瑞夫餐馆 乌苏拉好像喜欢我 我只点咖啡
I went back to Riff's. I think Ursula likes me. All I ordered was coffee.
她送了金枪鱼 三明治和四盘圈圈薯条
She brought me a tuna melt and four plates of curly fries.
得分
Score.
她好辣
She is so hot.
听好 你进一步行动前
Listen, okay, before you do anything Joey-like...
可能要先跟那个谁商量过
...you might want to run it by, uh...
- 真的？ - 对啊
- Yeah?     - Yeah.
- 菲比？ - 是
- Pheebs?     - Yeah?
我约你姐好吗？
Would it be okay if I asked out your sister?
干嘛？你干嘛要这样？
Why? Why would you want to do that? Why?
这样我们约会时 她才会到啊
So that if we went out on a date, she'd be there.
喔 我是说 我姐姐不归我…
Well, I mean, I'm not my sister's, you know...
那个…
...whatever. And, um...
虽然我们曾经是同一颗卵
I mean, it's true, we were one egg once.
但我们细胞分裂成两个人
But, you know, we've grown apart, so, um...
所以有何不可 好啊
I don't know. Why not?
赞 谢了
Cool. Thanks.
你没事吗？
You okay?
对 很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
要看西班牙片吗？
Do you wanna watch Laverne y Shirley?
抱歉
Sorry.
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.     - Hi.
抱歉 我迟到了 卡萝呢？
Sorry I'm late. Uh, where's Carol?
她学校有事 家长的事
Stuck at school. Some parent-teacher thing.
你不用参加 我来学就好
You can go. I'll get the information.
不 我应该留下来 我们俩都应该上课
No, no, ahem, I think I should stay. We should both know what's going on.
好
Oh, good.
这有意思了
This will be fun.
好了 我们先从基本的第三阶段呼吸练习开始
Alrighty. We're gonna start with some basic third-stage breathing exercises.
妈妈们 请躺好
Mommies, get on your back.
教练们 请撑好妈妈的头
And, coaches, you should be supporting Mommy's head.
- 什么？ - 什么？
- What?     - What?
难道要我演妈妈？
I'm supposed to be the mommy?
好吧 我只好再强调一遍 精子可是出自我喔
Okay, I'm gonna play my sperm card one more time.
我搞不懂为什么 就因为我是女人 就不能当教练
I don't see why I have to miss out on the coaching training because I'm a woman.
我懂了 那你建议如何？
I see. So, what do you propose to do?
- 来投硬币决定吧   - 投硬币？不…
- I'll flip you for it.     - Flip me for it? No, no, no.
那我选头
Heads, heads, heads.
躺下吧 孩子的妈妈
On your back, Mom.
好吧 各位妈妈 深呼吸 好好的伸展吐气
All right, mommies, take a nice, deep, cleansing breath.
很好
Good.
想象各位的阴部正在张开
Now imagine your vagina is opening...
像花儿一样
...like a flower.
狄先生 你好
Mr. Dee. How's it going, sir?
不算太好
Uh, it's been better.
年度使用数据出来了
The Annual Net Usage Statistics are in.
- 然后呢？ - 很难看
- And?     - It's pretty ugly.
打从70年代以来就没看过这么难看的年使数
We haven't seen an ANUS this bad since the '70s.
- 这代表何意？ - 不得不裁员了
- So, what does this mean?     - We're gonna be laying off people.
我知道上周我迟到了 但我睡得不好 头发很乱
Listen, I know I came in late last week. I slept funny and my hair was snarly.
不是要裁你
Not you.
别紧张
Relax.
你有过开除员工的经验吗？
Ever have to fire anyone?
妮娜
Nina...
Nina.
妮娜
Nina...
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
没事
Yes. Yes, I am.
这个呢 今天找你来呢
Uh, listen, the reason that I called you in here today was, uh...
拜托别恨我
Please don't hate me.
怎么了？
What?
今晚要共进晚餐吗？
Would you like to have dinner sometime?
菲比 你生日想要什么？
So, Pheebs, what do you want for your birthday?
真正想要我妈妈还在世 跟我一起庆祝
Well, what I really want is for my mom to be alive and enjoy it with me.
好吧
Okay.
这么说吧 要不要瑰珀翠高档身体用品？
Let me put it this way. Anything from Crabtree & Evelyn?
- 浴盐不赖   - 好 那就好
- Bath salts would be nice.     - Oh, okay. Good.
这是哪啊？
What is this place?
你说冷 我则想尿 窗户上有咖啡的图案
Look, you're cold, I have to pee, and there's coffee.
能坏到哪去呢？
How bad could it be?
有答案了
I think we have an answer.
她来干嘛？
What's she doing here?
这是上帝的旨意 要我们在家用餐别乱跑
This could be God's way of telling us to eat at home.
- 她被瑞夫餐馆开除了吗？ - 昨晚我们去时…
- Think she got fired at Riff's?     - No, we were there last night.
她一直送箭鱼来 你有要去…？
She kept bringing swordfish. Are you gonna go?
等我们点餐再去 毕竟是跟她点 对吧？
I'll wait until we order. It's her, right?
很像是她
It looks like her.
- 抱歉   - 怎样？
- Um, excuse me?     - Yeah?
是我们啊
Hi, it's us.
对 是我啊
Right. And it's me.
你也在这里？
So you're here too?
跟你们一样啊
As much as you are.
该你了
Your turn.
- 我们想点餐了   - 很好
- We know what we want.     - Oh, that's good.
- 两杯拿铁   - 一些饼干
- All we want is two caffe lattes.        - And some biscotti cookies.
不赖啊
Good choice.
- 绝对是她没错   - 对
- It's definitely her.     - Yeah.
真难以置信
I can't believe you.
结果你还是无法开除她？
You still haven't told that girl she doesn't have a job yet?
你也没拆圣诞灯啊
Well, you still haven't taken down the Christmas lights.
恭喜喔 你刚找了个最难吵起来的话题
Congratulations. I think you found the world's thinnest argument.
我只是想等到适当时机
I'm just trying to find the right moment.
应该不难 因为你们现在交往
Oh, well, that shouldn't be so hard, now that you're dating.
"亲爱的 你被开除了 不过上班前我们快快来一下如何"
"Sweetheart, you're fired. But how about a quickie before I go to work?"
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
既然人都进来了 就不用再敲门了
Once you're inside, you don't have to knock anymore.
我来开
I'll get it.
黑考斯先生
Oh. Hi, Mr. Heckles.
你们又在弄了
You're doing it again.
我们什么都没弄啊
We're not doing anything.
我们只是坐着静静聊天而已
We're just sitting around talking quietly.
我天花板很吵
I can hear you through the ceiling.
我的猫睡不着
My cats can't sleep.
你根本没养猫啊
You don't even have cats.
我本来可能养的
I could have cats.
再见 黑考斯先生
Goodbye, Mr. Heckles.
我们会小声点
We'll try to keep it down.
菲比 可以帮个忙吗？
Phoebe, can you do me a favor?
试穿一下看合不合身
Try this on to make sure it fits.
我这辈子第一次收到的生日礼物 真的很…
Oh, my first birthday present. Oh, this is really...
不是啦 这是送乌苏拉的 但我想你们一样身材
Oh, no, no. It's for Ursula. I just figured, you know, size-wise.
没问题 好
Oh. Sure. Yeah.
好 很合
Okay, it fits.
- 你又要约她了吗？ - 对 冰上嘉年华
- Are you seeing her again tonight?     - Yep, Ice Capades.
你们玩真的
Wow, this is serious.
我从没见过你肯为女朋友花钱
I've never known you to pay money for any kind of capade.
不知道 我就是喜欢她啊
I don't know. I like her.
她跟别人不同 她有某种特质
She's different. There's, uh, something about her...
让你迷上她 懂了 你喜欢她 很好
That you like. We get it. You like her. Great.
菲比 我事先问过你 你说没意见的啊
Hey, Phoebe, I asked you, and you said it was okay.
但现在有意见了
Well, maybe now it's not okay.
好吧
Okay.
但现在我对你有意见这事 很有意见了
Well, maybe now I'm not okay with it not being okay.
好吧
Okay.
快织 好女人 快织
Knit, good woman. Knit. Knit.
这边是克莱斯勒大楼
And that's the Chrysler Building right there.
哦
Oh.
- 妮娜   - 道格拉斯先生
- Nina.     - Mr. Douglas.
领带很正
Cool tie.
她还在
She's still here.
是 她还在
Yes. Yes, she is.
我不是有附纸条给你报告过
Didn't I memo you on this?
我开除她后 她的心理医师 法兰医师
See, after I let her go, uh, I got a call from her psychiatrist, Dr. Flanen...
发蓝医师
...Dr. Flanan, Dr. Flan.
告知我 她对开除一事适应不良
And, uh, he informed me that she took the news rather badly.
还用了"非常激动"这样的字眼
In fact, he, uh, mentioned the word "frenzy."
少开玩笑了 她明明就很…
You're kidding. She seems so...
没有 妮娜吗？她…
Oh, no, no. Nina? She's:
要是你去问她
In fact, if you asked her now...
她对被开除一事完全没有印象了
...she'd have no recollection of being fired at all.
太不可置信了
That's unbelievable.
却又很可信
And yet believable.
所以我决定 在确定她不会伤害自己
So I decided not to fire her again...
或其他人之前 不要再开除她一次
...until I'm sure she will be of no threat to herself or others.
好吧 人对事情的反应 真的很难预料
I see. Hmm. You never really know what's going on inside a person's head.
所以才有心理学吧 老板
Well, I guess that's why they call it psychology, sir.
毕竟 这是生产的奇迹
For this, after all, is the miracle of birth.
请开灯
Lights, please.
这就是生产的过程
And that's having a baby.
下一周就是最后一堂课了
Next week is our final class.
苏珊 往前跑
Susan, go deep.
太了不起了 真是太了不起了
It's impossible. It's just impossible.
什么东西了不起？
What is, honey?
刚才那女人…
What that woman...
的表现
...did.
我才不要经历那种事
I am not doing that. Heh.
只要宝宝不生出来就好了 那就一切依旧
It'll have to stay in, that's all. Everything will be the same.
- 只要不生出来   - 卡萝 亲爱的
- It'll just stay in. Ha, ha.     - Carol, honey. Shh.
- 会一切顺利的   - 你懂个屁
- Everything will be all right.     - What do you know?
又不会有人跟你说 "那是你的鼻孔吗？"
No one's saying to you, "Hi, is that your nostril?
可以把这肉块从这推出去吗？
Mind if we push this pot roast through it?"
卡萝 亲爱的
Carol, sweetie.
深呼吸吐气
Cleansing breath.
我知道这很吓人 但往远想一点
I know it's frightening. But big picture:
生产不过是那短短一天
The birth part is just one day...
等生完后 我们这辈子就成了人家的父母了
...and when it's over, we'll all be parents for the rest of our lives.
这么辛苦不就是为了这点吗？
I mean, that's what this is all about, right?
对吧 罗斯？
Ross?
罗斯
Ross.
我要当爸爸了
I'm gonna be a father.
- 你现在才想到吗？ - 我是知道会有个孩子
- This is just occurring to you?     - I always knew I was having a baby.
只是一直没想到 孩子也会有我
I just never realized the baby was having me.
你可以办到的
Oh, you're gonna be great.
你怎么知道？
How could you say that?
我连叫马塞尔别吃浴室踏垫都没办法了
I can't even get Marcel to stop eating the bathmat.
要怎么养育小孩
How will I raise a kid?
科学家说…
You know, Ross, some scientists are now saying...
猴子和小孩是不一样的
...that monkeys and babies are actually different.
- 去哪？ - 出去
- Where are you going?     - Out.
跟谁？
With?
是的
Yes.
问你一件事
All right, can I just ask you one question?
你们有那个了吗？
Have you two, you know, like, you know?
就那个
You know?
有没？
Yet?
虽然这不干你事
Well, not that it's any of your business...
但还没 可以吗？
...but no, we haven't, okay?
你是指做爱 对吧？
You meant sex, right?
- 有空吧？ - 有 妮娜 怎么了？
- Do you have a sec?     - Uh, sure, Nina. What's up?
不知道 过去几天 大家都躲着我
I don't know. For the past couple days, people have been avoiding me...
看到我表情都怪怪的
...and giving me these really strange looks.
喔 可能是因为…
Oh, well, uh, maybe that's because...
大家都嫉妒我们吧
...they're, uh, jealous of us.
可能
Maybe.
但他们收走剪刀 就说不通了吧
But that doesn't explain why they keep taking my scissors.
或许是因为要给你加薪了
Uh, well, maybe that's, uh, because you're getting a big raise.
- 有吗？ - 当然 有可能啊
- I am?     - Sure. Why not?
天啊 你好棒
Oh, my God. You're amazing.
还不只呢
Oh, you don't know.
海伦 请记得布克邦德小姐加薪的事 文件要弄好
Helen, make sure we put through the paperwork on Miss Bookbinder's raise.
那还要把她精神病历送到人事处吗？
Still want her psychological profile sent to personnel?
- 什么？ - 海伦有酗酒问题
- What?     - Helen drinks.
愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
- 最后我全盘托出   - 她反应如何？
- Well, I ended up telling her everything.     - Ooh. How'd she take it?
很好 除了钉书针
Pretty well. Except for the stapler thing.
小提示 要是遇到同样状况
Little tip. If you're ever in a similar situation...
手千万别放在桌上
...never, ever leave your hand on the desk.
我应该知道怎么操作了
Okay, I think I get how to do this.
可以关掉吗？可以弄走吗？
Can we turn this off? Can we make them go away?
因为我看不下去
Because I can't watch.
- 好了 菲比 关掉了   - 好
- Okay, Pheebs, they're gone.     - Okay.
- 你还好吗？ - 很好
- Are you all right?     - Yeah.
对 就是… 乌苏拉那事
It's just, you know, this whole stupid Ursula thing.
菲比 问你一句
Okay, Pheebs, can I ask?
他跟她约会就真的有这么糟吗？
So he's going out with her. Is it really so terrible?
有
Um, yeah.
不是说她很坏什么的
I mean, I'm not saying she's evil or anything.
但她老是坏了我的好事
She's just, you know, always breaking my stuff.
我八岁时 不肯借她儿童厨具组
When I was 8, I wouldn't let her have my Judy Jetson Thermos...
她就把厨具扔到车底
...so she threw it under the bus.
还有兰迪•布朗
And then there's Randy Brown...
他就…
...who was like...
你们有过青梅竹马般的男友吗？
Have you ever had a boyfriend who was like your best friend?
- 没有   - 没
- No.     - No.
他就是我青梅竹马的男友
Well, but that's what he was for me.
她却抢走他
And she, you know, kind of stole him away...
却让他心碎
...and then broke his heart.
之后他再也不理我了
And then he wouldn't even talk to me anymore.
因为他说不想再看到跟我们一样的人
He didn't want to be around anything that looked like either one of us.
菲比
Oh, Pheebs.
我清楚乔伊不是我男友 或儿童厨具组
I mean, I know Joey's not my boyfriend or my Thermos...
或什么 但是…
...or anything, but...
- 你不会失去他的   - 你要跟他谈开来
- You won't lose him.     - You gotta talk to Joey.
对 好
Yeah, okay.
他不会懂你的想法 如果他知道你这么想
Come on. He doesn't know this stuff. If he knew how you felt...
他爱上她了啊
He's falling in love with her.
拜托 才不过交往一周
Oh, please. They've been going out a week.
连床都没上过 根本不算什么
They haven't even slept together yet. I mean, that's not serious.
好吧
Okay.
好
Oh. Okay. Oh.
噢
Oh.
有什么事吗？
Yeah, um, may we help you?
待续
瑞秋 你干嘛啦？好冷喔 你到里头来好吗？
Rachel, what are you doing? It's freezing. Would you come inside?
不要
No, no, no.
是你叫我拆掉的
You wanted me to take them down...
那我就来拆啊
...so I'm taking them down, okay?
瑞秋
Rachel!
没事 我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
黑考斯先生
Mr. Heckles?
黑考斯先生 帮帮我
Mr. Heckles, could you help me, please?
我就说吧
See, this is just the kind of thing I was talking about.